Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Clement Greenberg papers
- Correspondence, 1937-1983, Series 3:; (Boxes 1-8; 7.0 linear feet)
  - Krupnick, Mark, 1976-1983 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - K, 1956-1983, (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 10-11)
  - Landfield, Ronnie, 1975-1979 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Lansdale, Phil, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Lapoussiere, Robert, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Leavis, F. R., 1954-1978 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Leavitt, Thomas, 1978-1983 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Limondjian, Hilde, 1981-1982 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Linder, Ernest, 1962-1965 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Link, John, 1980-1983 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Lochhead, Kenneth, 1957-1969 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Locke, Richard, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Louden, Bernadine, 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Louis, Marcella (Brenner), 1962-1974 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Louis, Morris, 1954-1965 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - L, 1954-1983, (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 25-26)
  - McCaughey, Patrick, 1970-1983 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - McCheshey, Clifton, 1965-1983 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - McClintic, Miranda, 1975-1979 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - McKay, Art, 1962-1981 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - McKay, Barbara, 1979-1983 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - McLean, John, 1977-1981 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - McLeavy, Peter, 1968-1976 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Mc, 1967-1983 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - MacMillan, J. Duncan, 1977-1980 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Maher, Donald, 1958-1968 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Manry, Lenita, 1950-1965 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Marcus, Stanley, 1974-1979 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Marshall, Margaret, 1950-1971 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Marshall, Neil, 1970-1972 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Martin, Richard, 1975-1983 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Mathieu, Georges, 1958-1969 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Matts, Freda, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Matzke, Shirley, 1977-1980 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Maytham, Thomas, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Meares, Ina, 1962-1966 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Medcalf, Gina, 1968-1983 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Mehring, Howard, 1962-1967 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Meier-Grafe, Anne Marie, 1950-1980 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Melzac, Vincent, 1964-1978 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Metropolitan Musuem of Art, 1970-1973 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Michalpoff, Ruth, 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Michigan State University, 1964-1973 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Mikl, Josef, 1977-1982 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Milby, David, 1964-1967 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Millard, Charles, 1964-1982 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Minkin, Marjorie, 1981-1983 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Mirvish, David, 1968-1982 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Moffett, Ken, 1963-1983 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Moffett, Marian, 1977-1981 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - Morales, Honorio, 1965-1967 (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - Motherwell, Robert, 1956-1981 (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Muller, Gregoire, 1974-1982 (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - Muller, Yvonne, 1974-1983 (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Murray, Gloria Maria, 1969-1973 (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Museum of Modern Art, 1965-1967 (Box 5, Folder 67)
  - Musselwhite, Ray, 1962-1969 (Box 5, Folder 68)
  - M, 1940-1983, (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 69-70)
  - Naifeh, Steven, 1979-1983 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Naomi Press, 1977-1983 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - National Endowment for the Arts, 1972-1973 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - National Gallery of Ireland, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - New Literary History, 1971-1972 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Newcomb, Stan, 1968-1974 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Newman, Barnett, 1955-1961 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Nims, John, 1961-1972 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Noland, Kenneth/Stephanie, 1962-1983 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - N, 1962-1983 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - O'Brien, John, 1982-1983 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - O'Reilly, William Edward, 1979-1983 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Ogburn, John/Marita, 1979-1983 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Olitski, Jules, 1962-1981 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Open University, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Oppler, Ellen, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Oxford University Press, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - O, 1966-1983 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Pace, Pamela/Steve, 1978-1980 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Parker, Ray, 1979-1983 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Parsons, Bruce, 1965-1966 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Partisan Review, 1970-1983 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Pascal, Suzanne, 1975-1979 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Paternosto, Cesar, 1965-1977 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Paterson, Doris, 1974-1975 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Peacock, Graham, 1975-1983 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Peebles, Don, 1970-1973 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Pejic, Bojana, 1978-1980 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Penguin Books, LDT., 1972-1974 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Pepper, Beverly, 1966-1969 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Perehudoff, Bill/Dorothy, 1963-1979 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Peters, Kenneth, 1965-1971 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Phillips, Gifford/Joann, 1962-1976 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Phillips, Sidney/William, 1950-1980 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Platschek, Hans, 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Pollock, Charles/Sylvia, 1958-1971 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Post Painterly Abstraction Exhibition, 1963-1964 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Postma, Bob, 1965-1967 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Prevot-Douatte, Myriam, 1960-1970 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Purcell, Ann, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Purohit, Vinayak, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - P, 1953-1983 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Querido, Zita, 1967-1968 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Quisgard, Liz Whitney, 1970-1973 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Rabinovitch, William, 1973-1980 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Ramos-Poqui, Guillem, 1980-1982 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Reyinto, Peter, 1974-1982 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Resika, Paul, 1968-1983 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Restany, Pierre, 1965-1978 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Retzer, Helga, 1976-1981 (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Reynolda House Lecture, 1972-1973 (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Reynolds, L. A., 1973-1983 (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Richter, Paul, 1981-1983 (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Risinger, Mary, 1980-1983 (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Roaldson, Robin, 1977-1979 (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Robertson-Swann, R. C., 1963-1968 (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - Rock, Arthur, 1971-1983 (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - ROSC, 1976-1980 (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - Rossi, Rosalie, 1969-1983 (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - Roth, Jennifer, 1982-1983 (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - Rubenstine, Angelica, 1966-1976 (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - Rubin, Beryl/William, 1963-1973 (Box 6, Folder 62)
  - Rubin, Lawrence, 1963-1974 (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - Ruenitz, Judy, 1974-1976 (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - Rumsey, Claire, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 65)
  - Russ, Anton, 1977-1979 (Box 6, Folder 66)
  - Russell, John, 1963-1974 (Box 6, Folder 67)
  - R, 1964-1983 (Box 6, Folder 68)
  - Sachs, A. M., 1967-1975 (Box 6, Folder 69)
  - Sailor, John, 1974-1980 (Box 6, Folder 70)
  - St. Martin's School of Art, 1964-1972 (Box 6, Folder 71)
  - Saito, Kikuo (Box 6, Folder 72)
  - Salem, Shelley, 1979-1980 (Box 6, Folder 73)
  - Sander, Ludwig (Lutz) (Box 6, Folder 74)
  - Sawyer, Kenneth, 1955-1956 (Box 6, Folder 75)
  - Schellhammer, Helen, 1972-1973 (Box 6, Folder 76)
  - Schimmel, Julie, 1971-1972 (Box 6, Folder 77)
  - Scott, Tim, 1967-1983 (Box 6, Folder 78)
  - Scrutton, Hugh, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 79)
  - Seidel, Brian, 1974-1979 (Box 6, Folder 80)
  - Seliger, Charles, 1966-1983 (Box 6, Folder 81)
  - Service, Pat, 1981-1983 (Box 6, Folder 82)
  - Shahvar, Cathy, 1982-1983 (Box 6, Folder 83)
  - Shaw-Eagle, Joanna, 1978-1980 (Box 6, Folder 84)
  - Shiff, Richard, 1980-1982 (Box 6, Folder 85)
  - Siegel, Jeanne, 1972-1980 (Box 6, Folder 86)
  - Sievan, Lee, 1970-1972 (Box 6, Folder 87)
  - Silcox, David, 1978-1981 (Box 6, Folder 88)
  - Silone, Ignazio, 1940-1942 (Box 6, Folder 89)
  - Silvermine Guild of Artists, 1976-1977 (Box 6, Folder 90)
  - Singer, Judy, 1975-1983 (Box 6, Folder 91)
  - Slone, Sandi, 1974-1983 (Box 6, Folder 92)
  - Smith, David, 1947-1964 (Box 6, Folder 93)
  - Smith, G. Roysce, 1962-1971 (Box 6, Folder 94)
  - Smith, Gaby/Kimber, 1962-1982 (Box 6, Folder 95)
  - Smith, Jean Freas, 1962-1978 (Box 6, Folder 96)
  - Smith, Karen, 1972-1974 (Box 6, Folder 97)
  - Smithsonian Institution, 1966-1980 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Southall, Derek, 1966-1983 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Staefel, Sheila, 1976-1978 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Stafford, Jean, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Stamos, 1978-1980 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Starkey, Alex, 1965-1971 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Starks, Gertrude, 1974-1975 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Snodderly, Daniel, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Stefanelli, Joe, 1977-1979 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Stein, Elaine/Robert, 1976-1982 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Steiner, Michael/Phyllis, 1968-1983 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Stern, Leni, 1971-1974 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Still, Clyfford, 1955-1961 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Stillman, Frances, 1976-1983 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Stoltz, David, 1975-1978 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Strelow, Hans, 1975-1981 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Stubbs, A. L., 1979-1981 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Studio International, 1965-1973 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Sutton, Patricia, 1981-1983 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Swan, Margie, 1977-1982 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Swayzee, Mary King, 1976-1980 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Syracuse University, 1972-1980 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - S, 1941-1983, (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 23-24)
  - Satransky, Valentin, 1978-1983 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Taylor, Paul, 1979-1980 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Thames and Hudson, 1972-1973 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Thorpe, Jo, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Thurman, Sue, 1971-1974 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Tillim, Sidney, 1967-1978 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Tint, Francine, 1982-1983 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Tobin, Richard, 1982-1983 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Toledo Museum of Art, 1971-1972 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Townsend, Peter, 1974-1978 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Trilling, Lionel, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Truitt, Alexandra, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Truitt, Anne, 1962-1983, (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 37-38)
  - Truitt, Mary, 1982-1983 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Tuchman, Maurice, 1964-1968 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Tyzack, Michael, 1974-1982 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - T, 1961-1983 (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - United States Information Agency/Service, 1961-1970 (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - University of California, 1966-1969 (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - University of Saskatchewan, 1962-1973 (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - U, 1963-1983 (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - Valliere, James, 1966-1968 (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - Vancouver Conceptual Art, 1969-1971 (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - Vandersluis, George, 1968-1980 (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - Vincente, Harriet, 1971-1982 (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - Virginia Polytechnic Institute, 1979-1980 (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - Vogue, 1963-1969 (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - V, 1950-1983 (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - Waddington, Leslie, 1962-1979, (3 folders) (Box 7, Folder 54-56)
  - Wagner, Anne, 1973-1974 (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - Wagner, Patricia, 1978-1983 (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - Wald, Alan, 1976-1977 (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - Walker Art Center, 1963-1969 (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - Walker, James Faure, 1975-1983 (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - Walsh, Jim, 1980-1982 (Box 7, Folder 62)
  - Waltzer, Stewart, 1973-1983 (Box 7, Folder 63)
  - Ward, Cora, 1964-1983 (Box 7, Folder 64)
  - Warmus, William, 1982-1983 (Box 7, Folder 65)
  - Washington Gallery of Modern Art, 1962-1965 (Box 7, Folder 66)
  - Wechsler, Judith, 1973-1975 (Box 7, Folder 67)
  - Wentzel Galerie, 1973-1983 (Box 7, Folder 68)
  - Werner, Winifried, 1976-1983 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Wernick, Bob/Marion, 1963-1982 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - West, Harvey, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Wetzel, Joanne Stewart, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Whitten, Jack, 1972-1980 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Witchita State University, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Willett, Don, 1969-1971 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Wilkin, Karen, 1973-1983 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Winston, Lydia, 1964-1967 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Woelffer, Emerson, 1963-1975 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Wolfe, Jim, 1976-1981 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Wolhandler, Larry, 1976-1979 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Wong, Jason, 1967-1968 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Wright, Bagley/Virginia, 1969-1983 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Wright, Merrill, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - W, 1960-1983 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - York University, 1970-1980 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Y, 1966-1983 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Zabriskie Gallery, 1964-1977 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Zador, Imre, 1980-1983 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Zaima, Stephen, 1981-1983 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Zechner, Karin, 1980-1983 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Zemans, Joyce, 1975-1978 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Z, 1970-1983 (Box 8, Folder 24)
- Artwork, 1973, Series 4:; (Box 8; 1 folder)
  There is one etching by Kurt Wisenski entitled "Spring."
  - "Spring" Etching by Kurt Wisenski, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 25)
- Writings and Notes, 1967-1983, Series 5:; (Box 8; 3 folders)
  Found are lists of artists and two reports written by Clement Greenberg about his visits to Japan and India, likely related to his work with the federal government. There are no manuscripts or drafts of his critical writing.
  - Lists of Artists, 1969-1983 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - "India Report," circa 1967 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - "Report on Japan Visit," 1967 February 4 (Box 8, Folder 28)
- Printed Material, 1950-1982, Series 6:; (Box 8; 2 folders)
  Found here are scattered exhibition announcements and clippings.
  - Clippings, 1961-1982 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Exhibition Announcements, 1950-1980 (Box 8, Folder 30)
- ACCESS Restricted Material, 1963-1983, Series 7:; (Boxes 9-11; 1.2 linear feet)
  Access restricted materials concern the David Smith estate, personal correspondence with family, Nuala O'Faolain, Peter Fuller, and Andre Emmerich, and sale and loan agreements. Contact the Archives' reference staff for information about access to this portion of the papers.
  The series is arranged as 3 subseries:
  7.1: David Smith Estate Materials, 1965-1982
  7.2: Correspondence, 1965-1980
  7.3: Sale and Loan Agreements, 1963-1974
  - David Smith Estate Materials, 1965-1982, 7.1:
    - Conservation Reports, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1965-1972 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1980-1982 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Expenses, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Inventories of Works of Art, 1974-1979, (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 4-5)
    - Legal Documents, 1965-1976 (Box 10, Folder 6-9)
    - Notes, 1966-1969 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Photographs of Works of Art, circa 1976 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Portfolio Appraisal, 1974 March 29 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Pricelists--Smith's Works, 1965-1980 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Printed Material, 1973-1974 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Slides of Works of Art, circa 1970s (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Summary of Trust, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1971-1983, 7.2:
    - Emmerich, Andre and Fuller, Peter, 1979-1980 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - O'Faolain, Nuala, 1971-1983 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Family, 1963-1974 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Personal Business Records, 1963-1974, 7.3:
    - Sale and Loan Agreements, 1963-1974 (Box 11, Folder 8)